hey guys it says no numbers are given
how many degrees is the red angle if you
want to try this on your own posit right
now because I'm going to solve it in
three two one let's focus on this
triangle and the semicircle anytime you
have a triangle inscribed in a circle
where one side is the diameter the
triangle will always be a right triangle
so this angle ACB has to be 90 degrees
and this is always true here's a nice
little visualization to show it if you
notice if we rotate the visual one side
will always stay horizontal and one side
always stays vertical that would only be
possible if it was a right triangle
since there's 180 degrees total in a
triangle these other two angles must add
to 90 degrees now once again that's
because we need all three of these
angles to add up to 180 degrees every
triangle has a special Point called the
in Center there are two very important
details about the in Center first it's
the center of the inscribed Circle and
second it's the intersection of the
angle bisectors so for this figure right
here Point m is the in Center it is the
the center of the inscribed Circle and
since these two lines intersect at that
point that means that these lines are
bisecting these two angles to make it
easier let's number these angles one two
and three so the measure of angle two
right here has to be half of the measure
of angle BAC now the same thing for
angle three it's cutting angle ABC in
half so we'd say the measure of angle
three is equal to measure of angle ABC
divided by two let's look at this
equation again and let's divide
everything by two the measure of angle
BAC divided by two that is the same
thing as the measure of angle two and
then we're going to add to that ABC
divided by 2 which is angle three and
that's going to be equal to 90 divided
by 2 which is 45 degrees and I'll smush
all this together and add angle one to
both sides of the equation angles one
two and three are the three angles of
this triangle so we know they're all
going to add up to 180 degrees and if we
subtract 45 degrees from both sides 180
degrees minus 45 degrees is 135 degrees
and on the right hand side we just have
the measure of angle one so the measure
of this red angle is 135 degrees and
that is the answer to the question let's
put a box around it how exciting